analog.com 2019-11-30

# Privacy & Security Statement | Analog Devices

__ You have accepted cookies. You have declined cookies.

* * *

### Additional Privacy Policy for European Economic Area (EEA) Residents

**Scope**

The statements below describe how ADI protects and uses data provided by web site visitors and ADI contacts from the European Economic Area (EEA). Unless outlined specifically below, terms specified in above Privacy & Security Statement will remain valid.

**Controller and EU Representative**

Analog Devices, Inc.  
One Technology Way  
PO Box 9106  
Norwood, MA 02062 USA

Our EU Representative is  
Analog Devices International U.C.  
Bay F-1  
Raheen Industrial Estate  
Limerick, Ireland

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

**Data We Use and Legal Bases for Processing Data for the EEA**

We process your personal data (first name, last name, phone number, job title, IP address, unique cookie identifiers) on several different legal bases, as follows:

  1. Based on necessity to enter into or perform a contract with you  

    * to enter into an agreement with you or a legal entity you represent
    * to perform contractual obligations
    * to respond to related questions and requests from you
    * to provide support
  2. Based on legitimate interests  

    * for the security and safety of our website, our IT connected to the website and the users of the website
    * to detect and prevent fraud
    * to understand website usage and present you with content and advertising based on your browsing activities and interests, provided you have not opted out of such data processing. Detailed information about the web analytics and advertising solutions used by analog.com are outlined below.
  3. Based on your prior consent  

    * for placing cookies on your device (subject to certain exceptions)
    * for sending marketing communications from ADI and our authorized distribution partners to you. Detailed information on our use of cookies and our marketing communications to you are outlined below.
  4. Based on legal obligations  

    * to comply with relevant laws, regulatory requirements and to respond to lawful requests, court orders and legal processes

**Marketing, Analytics & Advertising Solutions**

ADI uses several different third party marketing, analytics, performance and advertising technology solutions to provide an optimized customer experience on analog.com. The solutions used are listed below and will be updated as we continue to evolve and improve our customers’ digital experience. 

ADI uses these technologies for advertising and analytics purposes, such as to identify returning business visitors and display customized content. For more information on how to adjust your browser settings to delete or control cookies, please visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). For information on how to control internet-based advertising, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/). 

**Analytics / Performance**

**Adobe Analytics:**  
Understand and improve website usage and marketing campaign performance.  
Personal Data: IP Address, Email, website usage behavior

**iPerceptions:**  
Collect feedback on website performance from our visitors.  
Personal Data: Email, IP Address

**SessionCam:**  
Understand usability problems and help improve customer experience on our website. No personally identifiable information is collected during this process.  
Personal Data: IP Address, mouse clicks, movements

**Demandbase:**  
Enrich website usage data with company information based on IP address.  
Personal Data: IP Address

**Brightcove:**  
Understand video content usage.  
Personal Data: IP Address, analog.com video usage behavior

**Lithium:**  
Understand and improve EngineerZone community usage.  
Personal Data: IP Address, EngineerZone UserName, Email, EngineerZone community usage behavior

**Eloqua:**  
Understand and improve website usage and marketing campaign performance.  
Personal Data: IP Address, Email, First Name, Last Name, Job Title, Phone Number, Company Name and Location, website and email usage behavior

**Targeting/Profiling - Advertising**

**Google Adwords:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, improve user experience though offering more relevant content.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Google Retargeting:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message website visitors. Improve user experience though offering more relevant content.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**RhythmOne (formerly known as RadiumOne):**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Newbase:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Sizmek:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Dynadmic:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Bidtellect:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Quantcast:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Baidu:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Targeting/Profiling - Social Media**

**Facebook:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**LinkedIn:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Twitter:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Cookies Used on This Site**

Analog.com uses cookies as part of its services and to create a better user experience. ADI uses cookies for analytics and advertising purposes, such as to track the effectiveness of its marketing, to show you more relevant content, and for custom site functionality.

The cookies we use can be categorized as follows:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies:**  
These are cookies that are required for the operation of analog.com or specific functionality offered. They either serve the sole purpose of carrying out network transmissions or are strictly necessary to provide an online service explicitly requested by you.

**Analytics/Performance Cookies:**  
These cookies allow us to carry out web analytics or other forms of audience measuring such as recognizing and counting the number of visitors and seeing how visitors move around our website. This helps us to improve the way the website works, for example, by ensuring that users are easily finding what they are looking for.

**Functionality Cookies:**  
These cookies are used to recognize you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region). Loss of the information in these cookies may make our services less functional, but would not prevent the website from working.

**Targeting/Profiling Cookies:**  
These cookies record your visit to our website and/or your use of the services, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

To view a detailed list of cookies used on analog.com, [click here](https://www.analog.com/en/about-adi/landing-pages/001/cookies.html).

**Marketing Communications to You**

You can register to receive newsletters or similar information on our products and services by registering for a [myAnalog account](https://registration.analog.com/login/login.aspx). As part of the registration process, we ask you to provide us with certain required personal data such as first name, last name, email address, etc. 

When providing personal data to receive gated content, software, or other information/services, you are asked to provide consent for our processing of your personal data. You are under no obligation to provide such consent. You may choose to withdraw your consent at any time by:

  * Clicking the unsubscribe link contained in all emails sent by ADI
  * Updating privacy settings [here](https://www.analog.com/en/landing-pages/001/privacy-settings.html)
  * Sending us an email at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com)

**Recipients of Your Personal Data**

ADI will share your personal information with authorized third parties in connection with fulfillment of legitimate business uses that are intended to serve you, such as shipping products or materials requested by you. ADI also may share your information with our distribution partners and others in order for them to provide you with information about ADI and other products and services that we believe may be of interest to you.

ADI uses third-party platforms to store, analyze, and manage certain personal and other information, which helps ADI improve its operations, marketing and customer service and more effectively tailor our communications with you.

**Data Transfers to Recipients Outside of the EU/EEA**

We and many of our affiliated companies and third-party service providers are located outside of the EU/EEA.

To ensure an adequate level of protection of your personal data, we enter into data processing and data transfer agreements with our affiliated companies and third-party service providers outside of the EU/EEA that incorporate the provisions of the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the EU Commission or implement other appropriate safeguards with them. You can ask for a copy of these safeguards by contacting [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

**How Long We Keep Your Personal Data**

We have implemented appropriate retention periods for your personal data collected or otherwise processed on or through the website. Personal data processed in the context of a contract with you will be retained by us for the term of the contract and for a reasonable time afterwards as might be required to determine and settle any related claims. Where our processing of your personal data is based on legitimate interests or the compliance with legal obligations, it will be deleted as soon as the underlying purpose has expired. Personal data processed based on your consent will be deleted if and when you withdraw such consent.

**Your Rights Regarding the Processing of Your Personal Data**

In the EU/EEA, you have the rights to:

  * Inquire whether and what kind of personal data we hold about you and how it is processed, and to access or request copies of such personal data
  * Request the correction or supplementation of personal data about you that is inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date in relation to the purposes underlying the processing
  * Request the removal of personal data no longer necessary for the purposes underlying the processing
  * Request us to restrict the processing of personal data in certain situations where you feel its processing is inappropriate
  * Object, in certain circumstances, to the processing of personal data for legitimate interests
  * Request portability of personal data that you have actively or passively provided to us (which does not include data derived or inferred from the collected data), where the processing of such personal data is based on consent or a contract with you and is carried out by automated means

To exercise any of your rights above, please email a request to [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com). ADI will review and carry out valid requests. If the request is not deemed valid, ADI will share the reasons why it is not valid and your options for seeking resolution through a supervisory authority and through judicial remedy. You have the right to lodge a complaint against us. To do so, contact the authority in your country of residence.

**Your Provision of Personal Data to Us**

Your use of the website and your provision of customer data to us in the process is voluntary on your part. Subject to your sole discretion, you can stop using the website or opt out of certain data processing operations. An exception applies if you want to enter into or perform a contract with us on or through the website. In this event, providing us with your related personal information is necessary for us to be able to enter into the contract with or provide any contractual services to you.

**Effective Date and Changes**

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time by posted updated terms on this privacy page. Effective date is specified below. You should review the complete Privacy & Security Statement each time you visit our site to learn of any changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

This Privacy Policy is effective 5/25/2018. 

he European Economic Area (EEA). Unless outlined specifically below, terms specified in above Privacy & Security Statement will remain valid.

**Controller and EU Representative**

Analog Devices, Inc.  
One Technology Way  
PO Box 9106  
Norwood, MA 02062 USA

Our EU Representative is  
Analog Devices International U.C.  
Bay F-1  
Raheen Industrial Estate  
Limerick, Ireland

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

**Data We Use and Legal Bases for Processing Data for the EEA**

We process your personal data (first name, last name, phone number, job title, IP address, unique cookie identifiers) on several different legal bases, as follows:

  1. Based on necessity to enter into or perform a contract with you  

    * to enter into an agreement with you or a legal entity you represent
    * to perform contractual obligations
    * to respond to related questions and requests from you
    * to provide support
  2. Based on legitimate interests  

    * for the security and safety of our website, our IT connected to the website and the users of the website
    * to detect and prevent fraud
    * to understand website usage and present you with content and advertising based on your browsing activities and interests, provided you have not opted out of such data processing. Detailed information about the web analytics and advertising solutions used by analog.com are outlined below.
  3. Based on your prior consent  

    * for placing cookies on your device (subject to certain exceptions)
    * for sending marketing communications from ADI and our authorized distribution partners to you. Detailed information on our use of cookies and our marketing communications to you are outlined below.
  4. Based on legal obligations  

    * to comply with relevant laws, regulatory requirements and to respond to lawful requests, court orders and legal processes

**Marketing, Analytics & Advertising Solutions**

ADI uses several different third party marketing, analytics, performance and advertising technology solutions to provide an optimized customer experience on analog.com. The solutions used are listed below and will be updated as we continue to evolve and improve our customers’ digital experience. 

ADI uses these technologies for advertising and analytics purposes, such as to identify returning business visitors and display customized content. For more information on how to adjust your browser settings to delete or control cookies, please visit [http://www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/). For information on how to control internet-based advertising, please visit [http://optout.aboutads.info](http://optout.aboutads.info/). 

**Analytics / Performance**

**Adobe Analytics:**  
Understand and improve website usage and marketing campaign performance.  
Personal Data: IP Address, Email, website usage behavior

**iPerceptions:**  
Collect feedback on website performance from our visitors.  
Personal Data: Email, IP Address

**SessionCam:**  
Understand usability problems and help improve customer experience on our website. No personally identifiable information is collected during this process.  
Personal Data: IP Address, mouse clicks, movements

**Demandbase:**  
Enrich website usage data with company information based on IP address.  
Personal Data: IP Address

**Brightcove:**  
Understand video content usage.  
Personal Data: IP Address, analog.com video usage behavior

**Lithium:**  
Understand and improve EngineerZone community usage.  
Personal Data: IP Address, EngineerZone UserName, Email, EngineerZone community usage behavior

**Eloqua:**  
Understand and improve website usage and marketing campaign performance.  
Personal Data: IP Address, Email, First Name, Last Name, Job Title, Phone Number, Company Name and Location, website and email usage behavior

**Targeting/Profiling - Advertising**

**Google Adwords:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, improve user experience though offering more relevant content.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Google Retargeting:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message website visitors. Improve user experience though offering more relevant content.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**RhythmOne (formerly known as RadiumOne):**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Newbase:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Sizmek:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Dynadmic:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Bidtellect:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Quantcast:**  
Track and improve marketing campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Baidu:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Targeting/Profiling - Social Media**

**Facebook:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**LinkedIn:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Twitter:**  
Track and improve campaign performance, ability to re-message site visitors.  
Personal Data: Unique cookie identifier, analog.com page views

**Cookies Used on This Site**

Analog.com uses cookies as part of its services and to create a better user experience. ADI uses cookies for analytics and advertising purposes, such as to track the effectiveness of its marketing, to show you more relevant content, and for custom site functionality.

The cookies we use can be categorized as follows:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies:**  
These are cookies that are required for the operation of analog.com or specific functionality offered. They either serve the sole purpose of carrying out network transmissions or are strictly necessary to provide an online service explicitly requested by you.

**Analytics/Performance Cookies:**  
These cookies allow us to carry out web analytics or other forms of audience measuring such as recognizing and counting the number of visitors and seeing how visitors move around our website. This helps us to improve the way the website works, for example, by ensuring that users are easily finding what they are looking for.

**Functionality Cookies:**  
These cookies are used to recognize you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalize our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region). Loss of the information in these cookies may make our services less functional, but would not prevent the website from working.

**Targeting/Profiling Cookies:**  
These cookies record your visit to our website and/or your use of the services, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make the website and the advertising displayed on it more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.

To view a detailed list of cookies used on analog.com, [click here](https://www.analog.com/en/about-adi/landing-pages/001/cookies.html).

**Marketing Communications to You**

You can register to receive newsletters or similar information on our products and services by registering for a [myAnalog account](https://registration.analog.com/login/login.aspx). As part of the registration process, we ask you to provide us with certain required personal data such as first name, last name, email address, etc. 

When providing personal data to receive gated content, software, or other information/services, you are asked to provide consent for our processing of your personal data. You are under no obligation to provide such consent. You may choose to withdraw your consent at any time by:

  * Clicking the unsubscribe link contained in all emails sent by ADI
  * Updating privacy settings [here](https://www.analog.com/en/landing-pages/001/privacy-settings.html)
  * Sending us an email at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com)

**Recipients of Your Personal Data**

ADI will share your personal information with authorized third parties in connection with fulfillment of legitimate business uses that are intended to serve you, such as shipping products or materials requested by you. ADI also may share your information with our distribution partners and others in order for them to provide you with information about ADI and other products and services that we believe may be of interest to you.

ADI uses third-party platforms to store, analyze, and manage certain personal and other information, which helps ADI improve its operations, marketing and customer service and more effectively tailor our communications with you.

**Data Transfers to Recipients Outside of the EU/EEA**

We and many of our affiliated companies and third-party service providers are located outside of the EU/EEA.

To ensure an adequate level of protection of your personal data, we enter into data processing and data transfer agreements with our affiliated companies and third-party service providers outside of the EU/EEA that incorporate the provisions of the Standard Contractual Clauses approved by the EU Commission or implement other appropriate safeguards with them. You can ask for a copy of these safeguards by contacting [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

**How Long We Keep Your Personal Data**

We have implemented appropriate retention periods for your personal data collected or otherwise processed on or through the website. Personal data processed in the context of a contract with you will be retained by us for the term of the contract and for a reasonable time afterwards as might be required to determine and settle any related claims. Where our processing of your personal data is based on legitimate interests or the compliance with legal obligations, it will be deleted as soon as the underlying purpose has expired. Personal data processed based on your consent will be deleted if and when you withdraw such consent.

**Your Rights Regarding the Processing of Your Personal Data**

In the EU/EEA, you have the rights to:

  * Inquire whether and what kind of personal data we hold about you and how it is processed, and to access or request copies of such personal data
  * Request the correction or supplementation of personal data about you that is inaccurate, incomplete or out-of-date in relation to the purposes underlying the processing
  * Request the removal of personal data no longer necessary for the purposes underlying the processing
  * Request us to restrict the processing of personal data in certain situations where you feel its processing is inappropriate
  * Object, in certain circumstances, to the processing of personal data for legitimate interests
  * Request portability of personal data that you have actively or passively provided to us (which does not include data derived or inferred from the collected data), where the processing of such personal data is based on consent or a contract with you and is carried out by automated means

To exercise any of your rights above, please email a request to [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com). ADI will review and carry out valid requests. If the request is not deemed valid, ADI will share the reasons why it is not valid and your options for seeking resolution through a supervisory authority and through judicial remedy. You have the right to lodge a complaint against us. To do so, contact the authority in your country of residence.

**Your Provision of Personal Data to Us**

Your use of the website and your provision of customer data to us in the process is voluntary on your part. Subject to your sole discretion, you can stop using the website or opt out of certain data processing operations. An exception applies if you want to enter into or perform a contract with us on or through the website. In this event, providing us with your related personal information is necessary for us to be able to enter into the contract with or provide any contractual services to you.

**Effective Date and Changes**

We may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time by posted updated terms on this privacy page. Effective date is specified below. You should review the complete Privacy & Security Statement each time you visit our site to learn of any changes.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Statement, please contact us at [external.webmaster@analog.com](mailto:external.webmaster@analog.com).

This Privacy Policy is effective 5/25/2018.
